Guide to the Terry Sanford Papers, 1926-1996
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Terry Sanford papers 1926-1996
Sanford, Terry, 1917-1998
228.6 linear feet Extent: 130,000 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
RL.01134
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
However, some of the additions to this collection are not immediately accessible, because they require further processing before use.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The senatorial papers of Terry Sanford were received by the Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a donation in 1992-2000.
Accessions described in this finding aid: 2000-0408, 2007-0078, 2010-0059
Biographical Note
1917 Born in Laurinburg, NC
1939 A.B., University of North Carolina
1940-1941 Assistant Director, Institute of Government, University of North Carolina
1942 Married Margaret Rose Knight
1942-1945 Parachute Infantry, US Army
1946 J.D., University of North Carolina
1946-1948 Assistant Director, University of North Carolina Institute of Government
1948-1960 Private law practice in Fayetteville
1949-1950 President, North Carolina Young Democrats Club
1950-1953 Secretary-Treasurer, North Carolina Port Authority
1953-1954 North Carolina Senator
1956 and 1960 Delegate to National Democratic Convention
1961-1963 Chair, Southern Regional Educational Board
1961-1965 Governor of North Carolina
1964 Delegate, Democratic National Convention
1964-1967 Member, Carnegie Commission on Educational TV
1965- Partner, Sanford, Cannon, Adams, and McCullough
1965-1968 Director, Study of American States, Duke
1966 Publication: But What About the People?
1967 Publication: Storm Over the States
1968 Delegate, Democratic National Convention
1968-1969 Co-chair, Citizens' Committee for Governmental Reorganization; Chairman of Board, National Council of Independent Colleges and Universities; President, Urban America, Inc.
1969-1985 President, Duke University
1986-1992 U.S. Senator
Sanford served on the following U. S. Senate committees: Select Committee on Ethics (Chair); Special Committee on Aging; Budget; Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs including the Subcommittee on International Finance and Monetary Policy and Subcommittee on Securities; and Foreign Relations including Subcommittee on Near Eastern and South Asian Affairs (Chair), Subcommittee on African Affairs, and Subcommittee on Western Hemisphere and Peace Corps Affairs.
Collection Overview
The Terry Sanford Papers document Sanford's career as a United States Senator from North Carolina from 1986 to 1992. The collection contains papers dated from 1926-1992, with the bulk of the material dated between 1986 and 1992. His senatorial campaigns, views on issues, interactions with constituents, and activities in committees of which he was a member are documented throughout the collection. Sanford served on the following U. S. Senate committees: Select Committee on Ethics (Chair); Special Committee on Aging; Budget; Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, including the Subcommittee on International Finance and Monetary Policy and Subcommittee on Securities; and Foreign Relations, including Subcommittee on Near Eastern and South Asian Affairs (Chair), Subcommittee on African Affairs, and Subcommittee on Western Hemisphere and Peace Corps Affairs.
Senator Sanford's 1986 and 1992 campaigns are portrayed in the Press Files Series, particularly in the Videos Subseries and the Speeches Subseries. The Personal/Political Series contains Sanford's personal files from these campaigns. His views on the topics of education, health care, civil rights, foreign relations, and the environment are also documented in the Videos Subseries in interviews with Sanford and in campaign commercials; in the Speeches Subseries as well as in the Press Issues Subseries of the Press Files Series, and in the Voting Record Subseries of the Legislative Files Series.
Records of Sanford's activities on the committees on which he served (Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs; Foreign Relations; Budget; Select Committee on Ethics; Environment; and Appropriations) appear in the Legislative Files Series. His ideas and actions on the issues addressed by these committees are reflected in the General Correspondence Subseries of the Personal/Political Series.
Relationships with Sanford's constituents are documented in the Constituent Services Series. Both letters from constituents to Sanford and samples of standard form replies are included. Individual correspondence between Sanford and representatives of corporations and foundations are arranged alphabetically by the subject in the General Correspondence Subseries of the Personal/Political Series. The Videos Subseries of the Press Files Series includes lobbying material from industries.
Material in the Personal Journals Subseries of the Personal/Political Series is closed to patron use during Sanford's lifetime unless written approval from Sanford or his authorized representative has been acquired.
Several other area repositories hold collections pertaining to Senator Sanford's life and career. The Duke University Archives has records pertaining to Sanford's Presidency of Duke. Papers relating to his governorship are in the North Carolina Archives. His personal papers are among the holdings of the Wilson Library at the University of North Carolina.
Addition (1998-0323) is chiefly comprised of correspondence and printed material related to Sanford's political career, involvement in community, and membership in various organizations. They include files regarding the 517th Infantry (chiefly newsletters), a Battle of the Bulge reunion (1990), Central American affairs, and "miscellaneous memberships". Computer diskettes of Sanford's Senate journal document his career in the US Senate. (1982-1991) (780 items) (1.5 linear feet)
Addition (1999-0353) includes photographs and negatives of Sanford produced in 1987 for a senatorial portrait. (1987) (60 items) (.05 linear feet)
Addition (2000-0408) comprises 51 volumes of Sanford's Senate journal that cover June 1987 to August 1991; partial copies of his Senate schedules and 17 related micro-audio cassette tapes from July 1991 to March 1992; and other miscellaneous material concerning his senatorial campaigns of 1986 and 1992 and service in the Senate. This material was acquired from Sanford by Howard Covington and Marion Ellis for their use in writing Terry Sanford: Politics, Progress, and Outrageous Ambitions (Durham: Duke University Press, 1999). (1985-1995) (218 items) (3 linear feet)
Addition (2007-0078) (10 linear ft., 5650 items, dated circa 1986-1996) features material related to Sanford's 1986 senatorial campaign and to his book Outlive Your Enemies (published 1996). Senatorial campaign records include correspondence, voter surveys, campaign files, clippings, event flyers and invitations, videocassettes, and audiocassettes and other materials. The Outlive Your Enemies content consists of research files related to aging.
Addition (2010-0059) (3.6 lin. ft.; dated 1940s-1990s) includes hundreds of photographs from the Sanford family. The majority of these date from the 1980s and 1990s, while there are some earlier black and white prints from the 1940s and 1950s. Most are not labeled. There are also 2 photograph albums of family vacations to Africa (1988) and Europe (1990s). This material requires processing before use.
Addition (2012-0001) (0.2 lin. ft.; 150 items; dated 19602-2000s and undated) includes loose photographs and personal correspondence dating 1960s-2000s. The majority of these date from the 1970s. There are also miscellanous items including a 1987 Congressional Pictorial Directory. This material requires processing before use.
Subject Headings
Covington, Howard E.; Ellis, Marion A.; Sanford, Terry, 1917-1998; Terry Sanford: politics, progress, and outrageous ambitions.; United States. Army -- Parachute troops -- History; United States. Congress. Senate; United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs; United States. Congress. Senate. Select Committee on Ethics; United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on the Budget; United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Subcommittee on International Finance and Monetary Policy; United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Subcommittee on Securities; United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on Foreign Relations; United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on Foreign Relations. Subcommittee on Near Eastern and South Asian Affairs; United States. Congress. Senate. Committee on Foreign Relations. Subcommittee on African Affairs; Legislators -- United States; North Carolina -- Politics and government -- 1951-; United States -- Politics and government -- 1981-1989; Politicians -- North Carolina; Elections -- North Carolina
Contents of Collection
- Press Files Series, 1986-1992 and undated
  Press Files Series is divided into the following subseries: Clippings; Videos; Floor Statements; Speeches; Press Issues; Press Releases; TV and Radio Files; Newsletters; Editorials; Special Mailings; and Photographs.
  - Clippings Subseries, 1988-1992
    Clippings, primarily from North Carolina newspapers. Chiefly major news and feature stories about Sanford, the 1992 North Carolina Senatorial campaign, and various national campaigns.
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1988, May-1991, Nov., (21 folders) (Box 1)
    - 1991, Dec. -1992, Apr. 17, (20 folders) (Box 2)
    - 1992, Apr. 18-1992, June 24, (18 folders) (Box 3)
    - 1992, June 25-Sept. 13, (19 folders) (Box 4)
    - 1992, Sept. 14-Nov., (11 folders) (Box 5)
  - Videos Subseries, 1986-1992 and undated
    Videos cover interviews, campaigns, constituent relations, and lobbying material from various industries.
    - 1986-1990 (Box 6)
    - 1991-1992 (Box 7)
    - undated (Box 8)
    - Titles, undated (Box 9)
    - Audio cassettes, undated (Box 9)
  - Floor Statements Subseries, 1987-1992 and undated
    Floor statements addressed to Congress by Sanford and others.
    - 1987-1990, (23 folders) (Box 10)
    - 1990-1992, undated, (14 folders) (Box 11)
  - Speeches Subseries, 1986-1992 and undated(bulk 1986-1992)
    Speeches delivered during campaign appearances, for commencement addresses, and to civic organizations.
    Arranged chronologically, 1987-1994. Folders of miscellaneous speeches, 1986-1992, at end of series.
    - 1987:
      - Judge Junie Peel, 1987, Oct.1 (Box 12)
      - Interview at WTTG-Channel 5, 1987, Oct.7 (Box 12)
      - Fuqua School of Business, 1987, Oct.9 (Box 12)
      - Vance-Aycock Democratic Party Dinner, 1987, Oct.10 (Box 12)
      - University Values: The Age of the People, 1987, Oct.12 (Box 12)
      - Central America Plan, 1987, Oct.14 (Box 12)
      - Leadership for the Twenty-First Century and Beyond: The Role of Governor's School, 1987, Oct.22 (Box 12)
      - New York Times Publisher's Luncheon, 1987, Oct.26 (Box 12)
      - Before The Bank Capitol Market Association, 1987, Oct.29 (Box 12)
      - Central America, Talking Points, 1987, Nov.4 (Box 12)
      - Talking Points for Effective Schools Press breakfast, 1987, Nov.13 (Box 12)
      - San José speech, 1987, Nov.23 (Box 12)
      - University Values in the Ages of the People, 1987, Dec.4 (Box 12)
      - Spanish speech, 1987, Dec.10 (Box 12)
      - Deficit, 1987-1988 (Box 12)
      - Overseas Press Club, undated (Box 12)
    - 1988
      - Carolinas Council of Housing, 1988, Feb.8 (Box 12)
      - Reference Mike Dukasis Beyond the Summit, 1988, Feb.9 (Box 12)
      - Dedication of the Rufty-Holmes Senior Center, 1988, Feb.21 (Box 12)
      - Talking Points for Remarks to the ABA National Trust and Financial Services Conference, 1988, Feb.23 (Box 12)
      - The Importance of Education and Public Service in these Economic Times, 1988, Feb.25 (Box 12)
      - Gala fund-raiser, 1988, Feb.27 (Box 12)
      - The Struggle for Political Recognition, 1988, Mar.4 (Box 12)
      - Lenoir Rotary Club, 1988, Mar.4 (Box 12)
      - New Drum Majors for Justice, 1988, Mar.12 (Box 12)
      - In Conjunction with the 200th Anniversary of the Constitution The Ethical Responsibilities of Government Officials, 1988, Mar.21 (Box 12)
      - The Nation's Liability Crisis, 1988, Mar.26 (Box 12)
      - President Reagan's Radio Address, 1988,Apr. 2 (Box 12)
      - Reference Science, 1988,Apr. 2 (Box 12)
      - America, The Arts and Public Policy, 1988,Apr. 13 (Box 12)
      - Irons for the Ploughs, 1988,Apr. 14 (Box 12)
      - Talking Points for Breakfast Meeting with the OCC, undated (Box 12)
      - Budget Committee Field Hearing in Greenville, N.C., 1988,Apr. 20 (Box 12)
      - Suggested Talking Points for your Meeting with Secretary of Commerce Verity, 1988,Apr. 27 (Box 12)
      - Ahoskie Chamber of Commerce, 1988, May2 (Box 12)
      - Now That You Have Your Knowledge, What Are You Going To Do With It?, 1988, May4 (Box 12)
      - Leadership in the Eighties and Beyond, 1988, May10 (Box 12)
      - Talking Points Raleigh/Durham/Cary Chamber of Commerce, 1988, May18 (Box 12)
      - Taking Points Greenville Chamber of Commerce, 1988, May24 (Box 12)
      - Richmond Technical College Commencement, 1988, May28 (Box 12)
      - Duke University Marine Laboratory, 1988, June11 (Box 12)
      - Partners of the America's National Resource Council, 1988, June16 (Box 12)
      - Cotton Robinson, 1988, July7 (Box 12)
      - Fayetteville Tech R OASt, 1988, July19 (Box 12)
      - N.C. Democratic Student Summit, 1988, July29 (Box 12)
      - Central American Dinner, 1988, Aug.4 (Box 12)
      - The University of New Mexico Centennial Salute, 1988, Aug.11 (Box 12)
      - Soviet Nationalities Survey, 1988, Aug.22 (Box 12)
      - Remarks for Sam Katz dinner 9/30, 1988, Oct.21 (Box 12)
      - ABC Child Care and Parental Leave Bill, 1988, Oct.21 (Box 12)
      - Remarks for Acceptance of University Award, 1988, Nov.10 (Box 12)
      - N.C. Textile Manufacturers Association Annual Meeting, 1988, Nov.17 (Box 12)
      - Do Limited Educational Resources Perpetuate an Underclass?, 1988, Dec.2 (Box 12)
      - Gaston County Schools, U.S. History/Government students, 1988, Dec.6 (Box 12)
    - 1989
      - Statement of Senator Terry Sanford, 1989, Feb.1 (Box 12)
      - Student Government and Politics, 1989, Feb.3 (Box 12)
      - Motor Equipment Manufacturer's Association, 1989, Feb.27 (Box 12)
      - Terry Sanford: A Giant Oak of a Man, 1989, Feb.27 (Box 12)
      - Southern Technology Council Breakfast, 1989, Feb. 27 (Box 12)
      - B. N. Duke Scholarship Reception and Dinner, 1989, Mar. 3 (Box 12)
      - North Carolina Wildlife Federation, 1989, Mar.4 (Box 12)
      - The Greatest of Lincoln, 1989,Apr. 27 (Box 12)
      - Commencement Address: (Box 13)
        - Methodist College, 1989, May7 (Box 13)
        - Durham Academy, 1989, June3 (Box 13)
      - North Carolina A.F.L.-C.I.O. Meeting, 1989, June7 (Box 13)
      - Speech notes for Democratic women, 1989, June15-16 (Box 13)
      - Cherokee Indians, 1989, July21 (Box 13)
      - The Important Role of Historically Black Colleges, 1989, Oct.2 (Box 13)
      - Fannie Mae Press breakfast, 1989, Oct.20 (Box 13)
      - Speech to conference on Internally Displaced Persons, Georgetown University, 1989, Oct.16 (Box 13)
      - Welcoming Address by Senator Terry Sanford: SEACC National Conference, 1989, Oct.27 (Box 13)
      - Introduction of Science and Technological Literacy Act of 1989, 1989, Oct. 31 (Box 13)
      - Before the Triad Town Meeting on the constitution, 1989, Nov. 9 (Box 13)
      - Governor Augus W. McLean, 1989, Nov.9 (Box 13)
      - The Acceleration of History, 1989, Nov.13 (Box 13)
    - 1990
      - Speech for the Annual Eagle Scout Banquet, 1990, Mar.19 (Box 13)
      - Jefferson-Jackson Day Dinner, 1990, Mar.28 (Box 13)
      - Mecklenburg County Democratic Convention, 1990,Apr. 21 (Box 13)
      - Greetings to Chancellor James H. Woodward, 1990,Apr. 21 (Box 13)
      - (DCCC) David County Community College, 1990, May25 (Box 13)
      - Education Commission of the States, 1990, May (Box 13)
      - Chicago Area Consultation of Conscience, 1990, June10 (Box 13)
      - Response to Bush Appearance, 1990, June20 (Box 13)
      - Reagan's Mess, 1990, June29 (Box 13)
      - Justice James William Copeland, 1990, Oct.26 (Box 13)
      - To Turn the World Around, 1990, Dec.5 (Box 13)
    - 1991
      - Poverty in North Carolina: Z. Smith Reynolds Foundation, 1991, Jan.3 (Box 13)
      - OEF International 1991 Women in Development Awards Luncheon, 1991, May6 (Box 13)
      - Pembroke Commencement, 1991, May11 (Box 13)
      - Commencement Speech:
        - Dillard University, 1991, May23 (Box 13)
        - University of Toledo, undated (Box 13)
      - Interview with Senator Terry Sanford by Professor Elizabeth M. Hawthorne, the University of Toledo--Notes, 1991, June 14 (Box 13)
      - Job Corps, 1991, Sept.10 (Box 13)
      - Pinehurst, North Carolina: Health Care and The South: A Daunting Challenge, 1991, Nov.10 (Box 13)
      - Great Smoky Mountains National Park, 1991, Dec.11 (Box 13)
    - 1992
      - A Crusade for Children, 1992, May9 (Box 13)
      - Women's meeting, 1992, May20 (Box 13)
      - Sheriff meeting, 1992, July27 (Box 13)
      - Bicentennial Celebration for New Bern, undated (Box 13)
      - Speech materials: Reference quotes, undated (Box 13)
      - Speeches, 1986-1992, undated, (11 folders) (Box 13)
  - Press Issues Subseries, 1986-1992
    Press Issues in the form of clippings, notes, memos, and reports.
    Arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Agriculture, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Anti-Apartheid Act, 1988 (Box 14)
    - Appropriation requests, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Asheville building funds, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Bank Efficiency Act, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Banking Resolution Trust Corporation, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Black Males Heaving, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Brady bill, 1990-1991 (Box 14)
    - Budget, S.101, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Budget/Deficit, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Cable Consumer Protection Act, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Campaign Finance Bill, 1991-1992, (2 folders) (Box 14)
    - Campaign spending limits, 1990-1991 (Box 14)
    - Central America, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Charlotte Observer story, 1991-1992 (Box 14)
    - Children/Family/Welfare, 1988-1992 (Box 14)
    - Civil Rights, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Courts, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Crime Bill, 1991-1992 (Box 14)
    - Defense, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Democratic Housing Task Force, 1989 (Box 14)
    - Economy, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Education-S. 2, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Education, 1992 (Box 14)
    - Emergency Bank Investment Bill, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Emergency Bank Investment Corporation, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Energy Policy, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Environment, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Ethics Chair, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Ethics: D'Amato, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Fieldcrest Cannon Pension, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Head Stare, 1988-1990 (Box 14)
    - Health, 1990 (Box 14)
    - Health care, 1991-1992 (Box 14)
    - Housing, 1987-1990 (Box 14)
    - Interior: (Box 14)
      - 1988-1989 (Box 14)
      - Wildlife, 1988 (Box 14)
    - Iran-Contra, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Ivory Trade Ban, 1991 (Box 14)
    - Keating, 1990-1991 (Box 15)
    - King, M.L. Jr., 1989 (Box 15)
    - Labor, 1988 (Box 15)
    - Lawrence Lindsey Nomination, 1991 (Box 15)
    - Lumbee Indian Recognition, 1989-1991 (Box 15)
    - Middle East Subcommittee, 1987-1992 (Box 15)
    - Military, 1991 (Box 15)
    - Minimum Wage Bill, 1989 (Box 15)
    - Nags Head Woods Expansion, 1991 (Box 15)
    - National Affordable Housing Act, 1990 (Box 15)
    - NEA (National Endowment for the Arts), 1990 (Box 15)
    - Nominations, 1987-1989 (Box 15)
    - North Shore road, 1988-1991 (Box 15)
    - NTU (National Taxpayer's Union), 1992 (Box 15)
    - Nuclear, 1987 (Box 15)
    - Offshore Oil, 1991 (Box 15)
    - Press, 1987 (Box 15)
    - Rural Housing, 1989 (Box 15)
    - Rural Housing Conference, 1989 (Box 15)
    - Savings and Loan, 1991 (Box 15)
    - Securities Investor Disclosure Act, 1991 (Box 15)
    - Semiconductor statement, 1991 (Box 15)
    - Smoking, 1988-1990 (Box 15)
    - Spending in North Carolina, 1992 (Box 15)
    - Students, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Supply Side Economics, 1990 (Box 15)
    - Tennessee Valley Authority Lake Levels, 1991 (Box 15)
    - Textiles, 1986 (Box 15)
    - Toxic Waste, 1991 (Box 15)
    - Trade Press Releases, 1987-1991 (Box 15)
    - Transportation, 1990 (Box 15)
    - U.S.- Mexico Free Trade, 1991 (Box 15)
    - Womack Army Hospital, 1991 (Box 15)
  - Press Releases Subseries, 1986-1992 and undated
    Press Releases stating Sanford's position on legislation and proposals pertaining to U.S. Senate and North Carolina issues.
    - Press log, 1991-1992, (3 folders) (Box 15)
    - 1987, Mar. 9-1990, May 25, (14 folders) (Box 15)
    - 1990, June 4-1991, Oct. 9, undated(104 folders) (Box 16)
  - Miscellaneous Subseries, 1961-1992(bulk 1986-1992)
    Editorials; newsletters; television and radio files; and photographs.
    Arranged alphabetically by subject within these formats.
    - Editorials, Columns: (Box 16)
      - Commemoratives, 1987 (Box 16)
      - Farm column, 1987 (Box 16)
      - China, Most Favored Nation column, 1990-1992 (Box 16)
      - Flag Burning, 1989 (Box 16)
      - Rural North Carolina column, 1991 (Box 16)
      - Social Security column, 1990 (Box 16)
    - Newsletters:
      - 1987-1990 (Box 16)
      - Neighborhood notes ideas, 1989-1990 (Box 16)
      - Neighborhood notes, 1990-1991, (3 folders) (Box 16)
    - Newsletters, paste forms, 1988 (Box 17)
    - Television and Radio files:
      - 1989 (Box 17)
      - Campaign Finance Reform radio script, 1990 (Box 17)
      - Census 1990 Public Service Announcements, 1990 (Box 17)
      - Citizen's Conferences' Radio Spots, 1991, Mar. (Box 17)
      - Interview program, 1989 (Box 17)
      - North Carolina cable information, 1989 (Box 17)
      - The North Carolina Report, 1989, Oct. 28 (Box 17)
      - Radio feeds, 1989-1990 (Box 17)
      - Radio lists, undated (Box 17)
      - Satellite feeds, 1989 (Box 17)
      - Senate recording, 1988-1989 (Box 17)
      - Station lists, 1989 (Box 17)
      - Watch on Washington television series, 1989-1991 (Box 17)
    - Photographs:
      - 1986, Dec.-1990, Sept. 13, undated, (3 folders) (Box 17)
      - Negatives, 1986, Dec. -1992, undated, (7 folders) (Box 17)
      - Contact sheets, 1986, Dec. -1988, Aug. 4, undated, (3 folders) (Box 17)
      - Christmas card, 1989 (Box 17)
      - Newsletter, 1989-1990 (Box 17)
      - Photos received, 1986-1992, undated, (4 folders) (Box 17)
    - Betsy Sanford's 99th birthday, 1987 (Box 17)
    - Terry Sanford, 1960s (Box 17)
    - Misc., 1940-1990s, (2 folders) (Box 17)
    - Requests for autographs, 1987 (Box 17)
- Constituent Services Series, 1986-1992 and undated
  Constituent Services Series is divided into the Correspondence Management System Subseries and the Replies to Constituents Subseries.
  - Correspondence Management System Subseries, 1987-1988.
    Consists chiefly of letters to Sanford from constituents expressing opinions on issues and of samples of standard form letters or cover sheets sent in response. Also included are data reports listing constituents' names and their stances on issues.
    - Data reports, 1987, Feb. 19-1988, Dec. 5, (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - 1986, Dec. 17-1988, Mar. 14, (15 folders) (Box 18)